viewpointforum.com 2019-04-26

# Privacy Policy

_(Effective March 2017)_

MarketVision Research, Inc. is a full-service marketing research firm headquartered in the U.S. in Cincinnati, OH. As part of our business, we routinely collect data for the purpose of uncovering insights of relevance to our clients on a variety of topics. To the extent data collection (typically in the form of surveys) involves consumers or business professionals, the results are only used in aggregate with other data and with no personally identifiable information attached. 

We respect your privacy and confidentiality and will never make your personal information available to outside parties. Your information is used only as a way to group responses in providing feedback to our clients, and none of your specific information or responses are looked at on an individual basis. If individual responses are requested as part of research, you will be informed of the request and given the opportunity to opt-out and discontinue with the research **PRIOR** to any participation. 

MarketVision Research and Viewpoint Forum, our online panel and survey platform, strictly enforce the rules set forth by CASRO concerning the interviewing of respondents 13 years of age or younger, the [Children's Online Privacy Protection Act](http://www.coppa.org/ "Opens in a new window or tab") (COPPA) of 1998. If a survey requests the participation of a minor household member, under the age of 14 years, the rules outlined by COPPA will be followed. 

Any participation in research with MarketVision Research or Viewpoint Forum is voluntary. If, at any time, you wish to discontinue your participation please simply email us at [pverrill@mv-research.com](mailto:pverrill@mv-research.com) or [julie@viewpointforum.com](mailto:julie@viewpointforum.com "this will open your email application") and we will remove you from future participation. 

##  Privacy Shield 

MarketVision Research fully supports and is committed to complying with [Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/ "Opens in a new window or tab") principles guiding the collection, management, transfer, and storage of data we capture and maintain from marketing research activities, and operates under jurisdiction of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). 

###  Notification 

  * Any and all data collected by MarketVision Research or via Viewpoint Forum is done so by permission of the respondent providing data.
  * Any and all data collected by 3rd party suppliers are contractually obligated to comply with MarketVision's policies for data handling/management.
  * The nature of any research is communicated upfront and with full transparency.
  * A notification will be sent to respondents via email to gain their cooperation. If at any time you wish to no longer be emailed for surveys or other research purposes, or any purpose at all, you will be removed from future notifications.
  * Any references to deadlines for completion and incentives to be earned are clearly communicated in this notification.
  * Research participants have the right to know what data is being collected from them and the manner in which it is to be store and used.
  * Research data and any personal information will be stored solely for the purpose of the research and only kept as long as necessary to complete the research.

###  Choice 

  * MarketVision Research and Viewpoint Forum strictly abide by [Insights Association](http://www.insightsassociation.org/ "Opens in a new window or tab") rules of participation. You can opt-out of any and all participation at any time with no penalty or hesitation. Your participation is entirely voluntary. To opt-out, email either [pverrill@mv-research.com](mailto:pverrill@mv-research.com) or [julie@viewpointforum.com](mailto:julie@viewpointforum.com "this will open your email application").
  * If there's an opportunity to participate in a non-survey research activity, and if this opportunity includes any sort of media or self-identification, you will always be asked for permission to participate in said activities **PRIOR** to collection of data. You can continue participation in other research activities and choose not to participate in anything that identifies you in special research requests, with no penalty or hesitation. All participation is by permission only.
  * You may discontinue your participation in research with MarketVision Research or Viewpoint Forum at any time.
  * Any communication requesting participation by others in the household will be clearly communicated to the primary research participant, with no requirement for participation. Data remains secure via all Insights Association guidelines.

###  Onward Transfer 

  * Any data to be transferred for any reason is limited and for specified research purposes only.
  * Any vendors or third parties working with or for MarketVision Research are contractually obligated to comply with MarketVision Research guidelines for confidentiality and data security, and in compliance with Insights Association requirements.
  * Third party partners include research companies and agencies that assist in the execution of research. These partners assist in global data collection in the form of surveys or transcription of qualitative interviews, both online and offline. These partners are required to maintain privacy and security levels equal to or greater than Privacy Shield guidelines.
  * When transferring data to a third party acting as an agent, the agent is obligated to provide at least the same level of privacy protection as is required by Privacy Shield.
  * When acting as a controller, any third parties to whom data is transferred are obligated to maintain at least the same level of privacy protection as required by Privacy Shield.
  * MarketVision recognizes it may be liable for violations which occur during onward transfer to third parties.

###  Access 

  * You have the right to know what information has been collected as a result of your research engagement with MarketVision Research and/or Viewpoint Forum. If at any time you have questions about what's being collected, email us at [pverrill@mv-research.com](mailto:pverrill@mv-research.com) and we can respond accordingly.

###  Security 

  * MarketVision Research retains data only on secured servers in secured facilities.
  * We will never rent or sell your data for any purpose. Data is used strictly for research purposes.
  * Any personally identifiable information is secure and data is reported only in aggregate. In the rare exception that we would like to share information that could identify you as a participant, your permission will be acquired **PRIOR** to collection of data and there is no requirement to participate.

###  Data Integrity 

  * All research data is kept strictly confidential and never shared for any reason outside of the expectations for the research.
  * All personally identifiable information that we collect is done so by permission only, and data stored on secure servers.
  * No personally identifiable information is ever shared without your permission.
  * All personal information we collect is relevant for the purpose for which it is to be used and that to the extent necessary, we take reasonable steps to ensure data is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete and current.

###  Enforcement 

  * MarketVision ensures its employees comply with Privacy Shield principles and is committed to providing training and policy updates to each employee at minimum once every 12 months.
  * Research participants may bring a complaint directly to MarketVision Research at any time, at no cost to the participant, and expect a response within 45 days of the filing date. In addition, any complaint filed to a data protection authority (DPA) in the EU will be reviewed by the Department of Commerce and best efforts taken to facilitate resolution of the complaint and to respond to the DPA within 90 days.
  * In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, MarketVision Research commits to resolve complaints about our consumer's privacy and our collection or use of consumer's personal information. Anyone with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact MarketVision Research at:  MarketVision Research, Inc.  
Attn: Bob Graff  
5151 Pfeiffer Road, Suite 300  
Cincinnati, OH. 45242  
  * MarketVision may be required to disclose personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including meeting national security or law enforcement requirements.
  * Under certain limited conditions, individuals may invoke binding arbitration before the Privacy Shield Panel to be created by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Commission.

MarketVision Research has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles to the INSIGHTS ASSOCIATION PRIVACY SHIELD PROGRAM, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Insights Association. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit <http://www.insightsassociation.org/get-support/privacy-shield-program/privacy-shield-eu-swiss-citizens-file-complaint> for more information and to file a complaint. 

##  Insights Association Privacy Shield Independent Recourse Program 

MarketVision Research is dedicated to ensuring your personal privacy. We strictly adhere to Insights Association guidelines for proper data protection, and are contracted with Insights Association's Privacy Shield Program to ensure security of data between the U.S and the EU. As part of our self-certification to the Privacy Shield program, we are compliant with the privacy principles and frequently asked questions (FAQs) of the Privacy Shield Framework as developed by the U.S. Department of Commerce in consultation with the European Commission. 

To learn more about Privacy Shield, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/ "Opens in a new window or tab"). 

To verify our compliance with Privacy Shield, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>

Contact information questions, comments or complaints regarding the Company's Privacy Policy and compliance with Privacy Shield can be mailed or emailed to: 

MarketVision Research, Inc.  
Attn: Bob Graff  
5151 Pfeiffer Road, Suite 300  
Cincinnati, OH. 45242  
Effective Date: March 27, 2017
